迈克 · 诺斯: 之前我们有一个关于
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Earlier we had
a question about the difference between
接口和类型别名。
interfaces and
something called type aliases.
这两种方法都可以给结构起一个名字，我们可以导入
And these are both ways of giving
a structure a name that we can import and
从模块导出，我们可以参考。
export from modules, and we can refer to.
主要的好处是我们有一个定义类型的中心位置，并且
The main benefit is we have one central
place where a type is defined, and
它可以在整个代码库中使用。
it can be used throughout a code base.
所以我们要学习这两个概念，比较和对比它们。
So we're gonna study these two concepts,
and compare and contrast them.
一路上，我们会谈到不同类型的签名
Along the way, we're gonna touch on
different types of signatures which
包括我们用来调用函数的签名
includes the kind of signature we're
used to for invoking a function, and
一种叫索引签名的东西。
something called an index signature.
我们将讨论开放接口的概念，这是一种你可以
We will discuss the idea of open
interfaces, and this is a way that you can
增加可以从某个库导入的类型。
augment types that you may
import from a library somewhere.
我们将讨论访问修饰符关键字的概念，它给我们提供了控制
We will discuss the concept of access
modifier keywords which gives us control
谁可以看到方法
over who can see methods and
当涉及到类时，使用实例数据。
instance data when it comes to classes.
最后我们会谈到遗产条款，这只是一个花哨的名字
And finally we'll touch on heritage
clauses which is just a fancy name for
延伸，对吗？
extends, right?
您习惯于从 JavaScript 类扩展。
You're used to extends
from JavaScript classes.
有一个新的叫 implements 的东西是和打字稿一起出现的。
There's a new one called implements
that comes with with TypeScript.
我们打开笔记，翻到以三开头的页面,
So we'll open our notes to
the page that starts with three,
接口和类型的基础知识。
interface and type basics.
类型别名，一个非常简单的概念。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Type aliases,
a really simple concept.
它实际上是给一个类型命名。
It is literally giving a type a name.
任何可以与变量一起使用的类型，也可以为。
Any type that you can use with a variable,
you can also create a type alias for.
所以，当我说字符串或
So, when I say string or
麦克 · 诺斯: 我的意思
number here,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: What I mean
这里是任何可能存在于这个空间中的东西，您可以为。
here is anything that could exist in this
space, you can create a type alias for.
对于接口来说，情况并非如此。
This is not true for interfaces.
所以类型别名实际上在某些方面比接口更灵活。
So type alias is actually more flexible
than an interface in some way.
这是你唯一一次在右手边看到一个字体
This is the only time you'll ever
see a type up here on the right hand
平等的一面。
side of an equals.
嗯，还有一个，但是，它真的是一模一样的
Well, there is one other but,
it is really the identical
只是语法稍有不同
concept just in a slightly
different syntax, but
我们只在这里寻找字体空间。
we're exclusively looking
in type space here.
这将根本无法编译成 JavaScript。
This will compile to no JavaScript at all.
Mike North: 类型别名的挑战之一是它们被定义为和
&gt;&gt; Mike North: One of the challenges with
type aliases is that they are defined and
由编译器根据什么值来计算
figured out by the compiler
in terms of what values
是允许的，在文件被解析时排成一行。
are allowed,
in line as the file is parsed.
这会阻止你创建自我尊重的类型。
And this prevents you from
creating self reverential types.
假设我们有一个数据结构，我们想为它创建一个类型,
So let's say we had a data structure
that we wanted to create a type for,
看起来像这样。
that looked like this.
1,2,3,1,1.
&gt;&gt; Mike North: 1, 2, 3, 1, 1.
对，它由1、2和3组成，还有一个嵌套数组。
Right, it consist of 1s, 2s and
3s, but also a nested array.
非常简单的那种类似 JSONish 的东西。
Really simplified kinda JSONish thing.
就像在一组允许的值中有一些层次。
Like there's some hierarchy here
in a set of allowed values.
我们可以尝试输入这个值可以是1,2或者
We could try to type this saying
that the value can be 1, 2 or
3，或者数组，其中数组是 NumVals 数组。
3, or an array,
where an array is an array of NumVals.
编译器不高兴，原因是,
Typescript compiler is not happy,
and the reason is,
它想要最终弄清 NumVal 到底是什么,
it wants to conclusively figure
out what NumVal is all about,
然后移动到下一行，它还没有遇到这个。
before it moves on to the next line,
and it has not yet encountered this.
所以，它遇到了一个循环问题。
So, it runs into a circular problem.
这就像一个鸡和蛋的问题。
It's like a chicken and the egg problem.
为了定义 a，我们需要 b，它需要 a，所以沿着这条路一直走下去。
To define A we need B which needs A,
and so follow that all the way down.
所以，我们会回过头来看这个问题，并解释这个问题是如何产生的。
So, we will look back to this and
explain how this can be.
我们可以利用我们的优势。
We can use to our advantage.
我们可以利用这个弱点作为优势。
We can use this weakness as strength.
迈克 · 诺斯: 我们已经看过界面了。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So
we've already looked at interfaces.
我想指出的是接口可以从其他接口扩展,
I wanna point out that interfaces
can extend from other interfaces,
就像你习惯在类中看到的一样。
like same syntax that you're
used to seeing with classes.
请记住，extends 用于类似事物的继承。
Just remember that extends is used for
inheritance of like things.
接口从接口扩展，类从类扩展。
Interfaces extend from interfaces,
classes extend from classes.
所以在这里我们只是添加国家代码的东西，已经
So here we're just adding country
code to something that already
有电话号码和名字。
has a phone number and a name.